The credit for today's video goes to the comment of this gentleman.
Thank you for your comment sir.  As you all know that
every day every video on the channel
comes as per your questions, suggestions and comments.  So stay connected to the channel.
For that, like and share the video.
Subscribe to the channel and
turn on all notification bells so that
you get all the latest videos and updates on time
and do tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be related to.
Hello everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're watching You the Real.  I
am your personal advisor Amit Raj
Sharma.  In today's video, we will learn about the Super Term Plan of
Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited as per the comment of Mr.
This plan is a
non-linked non-participating life
individual pure risk premium plan.
In simple words, the premium
you pay will
not be subject to any market-related risk and the
benefits within the plan will not depend on the
performance of the company in any way.  That
means he will not be dependent on bonus.  That means,
according to the premium you are paying, you will
get life insurance and other benefits of the plan will
also be given to you.  Depending on whichever option you
choose because there are
three different options in the plan.  The first is level cover,
in which the number of points you choose through the positive remains the same.  The
second is
increasing cover in which your cover
amount keeps increasing which you
call sum.  The third is level cover with return
of premium.  The sum assured you choose will remain the same
throughout the policy term and at the end,
you will get back the base premium you paid.  If we view the
video on full screen,
we will find that the
entry age limit for option number one and option number two of the plan is from 18
years to 65 years and
for option number three the entry age limit is from 18 years to 55 years.  The
maturity age limit in the plan ranges
from 28 years to 85 years.  This means that
you will be able to remain under cover for a maximum of 85 years.
Premium Payment Term Limited premium
payment term option is available with plan option number
one and two in which you can pay premium for 5 years, 10 years,
12 years, 15 years, 20 years or
till the age of 60 years.
With plan option number three, there are
three options for limited premium payment term.  5
years, 10 years and 15 years.  Regular Pay
means that
your policy term will be equal to the number of years of the premium payment term.  In
which the policy term will be from 10 years to 55 years.
In case of limited premium payment term,
you will add 5 more years to the premium payment term and
your policy term can be up to a maximum of 55 years.  The
minimum sum assured limit is ₹25
lakh.  The maximum sum limit
depends on the company as to
how much it approves you as per the board approved underwriting policy rules.  The
premium will depend on
which plan option you have chosen.
How is your health?  How is the lifestyle?  What is Edge?
What is gender?  What Mode of Premium are you choosing
?  Right and premium payment term depending on what you
took.  Ok?  Now we will know about the benefits of Super Term Plan of Aditya Birla
Sun Life Insurance Company Limited.  The
first is terminal inelasticity.
Terminal illness is expected to be a disease
that may result in the death of the insured within the next 6 months
and this is being said on the basis of the diagnosis reports of not one but
two medical professionals i.e. doctors.
If
this happens before the age of 80, then you will get 50% of the sum assured
i.e. the sum assured on death which is the life
cover.
Its maximum limit is up to ₹1 crore.  Because
your sum assured can be any amount.  Right?
And if there is death in future, then the
terminal illness cover already received will be deducted from the sum assured on death.
You will get only the rest amount.  That is, your
nominee. Second is Waiver of Premium and
Accidental Total and Permanent Disability.
One condition for this is that
the cover will be available only till the age of 70 years.  The
names of the disabilities are on the left hand side of the
screen.  Please pause and read it.
You will have to report that it has become a
permanent accidental disability within 60 days from the date of the accident.
And if this permanent accidental disability
persists for 180 days for the insured,
then it is counted.  In such a situation, the company
then pays all the future premiums itself.
Third is the X-related critical
illness benefit.  Now the criticality is 42
whose names are on our left hand side
screen.  There is a
waiting period of 90 days for X-related critical illness benefit.
After taking the policy,
you have to wait for 90 days.  Right?  Minimum cover is up to ₹5 lakh.
50% of the maximum sum assured or
say Rs 50 lakh, whichever is less.   That
means the maximum limit is up to Rs 50 lakh.
Because you can take your sum assured of Rs 1 crore or Rs 2 crore.
So in that case, the
limit mentioned here is maximum and this amount gets
deducted from the death benefit
because this accelerated benefit is
not separate.  Ok?  Benefit number four is the
staggered death benefit, which is expected to allow the
nominee to take the death benefit in installments over the next five years if they wish.  That
means
they can take it in monthly installments over a period of 5 years.
If he
takes the death benefit in monthly installments, then the
monthly installment here will be
1.8534% of the death benefit.
Overall, if you total the
death benefit over a period of 5 years, it will
amount to 111.20% of the death benefit.  You also get early exit value in
which you get back whatever base premium
you have paid.  But the
condition is that the age should be between 60 to 70
years and
30 years of the policy should be completed.  Obviously,
if 30 years are completed, then anyone can
exit the plan and
get back his paid premium.  This option
number one and option number two
is available with which plan option number one and two and
you cannot take early exit value in the last 5 years of the policy.
Continuous benefit cover is available
with plan options number one and two.  The hope is that
suppose a time comes when
you are not able to pay the premium for the next 12 months.
So, in such a situation,
your life cover will continue as it is through Cover Continuous Benefit
and in future
you will pay the premium without any
extra charges and if death occurs within these 12 months, then the
amount of unpaid premium will be deducted
from the death claim.  Benefit number seven here is
change in premium payment term.  If
you want the option to change the premium payment term, then the plan
is available only with option number one and two.  As soon as there are
30 days left for the completion of the policy year,
you will be
able to make the change in premium payment by making a request.  The Enance
Life Stage Protection Benefit
is available with options one and three.
You will be able to increase your life insurance on your first marriage.
Up to 50% of your sum assured.  The maximum amount
cannot exceed ₹50 lakh.
You will also be able to increase the amount on the birth of two children, but the
child birth limit is 25% of the basic sum assured i.e. up to
₹25 lakh.
Even if you are building your first house, you can increase your basic sum by up to 50%.
What will be the amount limit?  ₹50 lakh.  But when will you be
able to exercise?
You will have to do this exercise before you reach the age of 50.  You will be
able to use Enhanced Life Stage Protection only if your premium payment term is either more than 5 years or at least 5 years and there is no claim of any kind.  Right?  Instant Payment on
Claim means if your policy
is in force and you have completed 3 years of the policy,
3 years after the revival period or
3 consecutive years from the beginning.  Ok?  So in such a situation, the amount of ₹1 lakh will be
received as instant claim.  If the problem is between ₹50 lakh to ₹1
crore.  If the sum assured is more than ₹1 crore,
then the nominee will immediately get ₹1 lakh
within the With-in-a-One Working Deeds
because at the time of death, there are expenses and it happens
that sometimes the situation becomes such that
someone does not have money, then
he can claim from the company and gets With-in-a-
One Working Deeds.  Now the names of the
riders available in this plan are on the
top of the screen.  Please pause and read it.
Check out the rider playlist.
Link in the description of the video from there
you will find videos of the rider.
You have to choose the death benefit payout option at the time of purchasing the plan.  There
are three options.   The
first is lump sum in which the lump sum
benefit i.e. sum is immediately given to the nominee.  The
plan is closed.  The second
is income, in which while taking the plan, you
choose what percentage of your sum on
death will be given to your nominee for how many months.  The
third is Income Plus Lumpsum, in
which the range is from 10% to 90% of
your sum assured amount, which is
given to the nominee in the form of income benefit, that is,
while taking the plan, you will decide how much
percentage the nominee should get as lumpsum and
how much should be given in monthly installments.  The income
period is 10 years, 15 years and 20 years.   From
this, you have to choose for how many
years you want to give the benefit in the form of income benefit to
your nominee in the event of
your death.  In the increasing cover option,
I did not tell you
how much the life insurance will increase.  So here it
is simple that in the increasing cover option you take,
your sum assured will keep
increasing by 5% every year until your sum assured
doubles.  That means if the
sum assured is Rs 1 crore then it should not become Rs 2 crore.  Along with
this, you get the Health Management Service
option which is an add-on service
for which you will pay, in that you will be
able to get medical opinion etc. extra and if
we make the video on full screen then the
policy brochure tells us that if you are a
healthy male and a non-smoker and
take a sum assured of ₹1 crore and
want to remain under the cover till the age of 85 years,
you choose the regular premium payment term option
and if you take the death benefit lump sum option
and if your age is 30 years then in
such a case the policy term will come, 30 will be subtracted from 85, that is 55
years, that is the
premium payment will be for 55 years only.  If you take plan option
number one, you will have to pay a premium of ₹18,500 annually.  If you
choose plan option number two, you will have to pay an annual premium of ₹42,300. If you choose plan option number
three, you will have to pay an annual premium of ₹27,800.  There
is no tax involved in this.  If you choose the death benefit option, you will choose the income
option, that too with a period of 20 years.  If your
age is 30 years then
you will have to pay ₹14,800 with plan option number one.  If you
take the increasing cover option i.e. plan option number two, you will have to pay ₹33,840.
If you take plan option number three
then
you will have to pay ₹22,240.  For how many years?  Up to 55 years.
Because the premium payment
term here is 55 years as it is the regular premium
payment term.  55 years is a positive
term.  Apart from this, I will bring a separate video in
which
I will explain each option in detail with an example.  So
stay connected with us by subscribing to the channel.
Tell us in the comment section.  The next video will be about
a plan if you want.
Thanks you all.  Take care of yourself.
Understand one thing yourself.  Explain to others that
insurance is a protection.
Never take incomplete protection.  Thank you.
[music]